Anthony Guillermo

43 St. Erkenwald Road Barking, Essex, IG11 7XA Mobile: 0782 599 8307 Tel: 0208 594 4401

E-mail: a.guillermo8@yahoo.com

Personal Statement

I am a BA Accounting & Finance Post Graduate and Part Qualified ACCA member, with a view to one day become a professionally qualified Accountant. I have worked for a year as an Accounts Assistant, and then progressed to Credit Controller in Genix Imaging Ltd. My current role is working as a MIS/Operations Support in Philippine National Bank (Europe) Plc. Where I advanced from starting position of Teller to Giro Processor to Accounts Recon and then to my current position today. I also have a passion for photography. My main goal is to never stop learning and continue to grow step by step, so I can be the best that I can be in no matter what field of work I do.

Education

Dagenham Park Community School 2000-2005:

GCSE's - English (B), Maths (B), Double Science (BB), ICT (B), Geography (B), History (B), Music (C)

Dagenham Park Community School Sixth Form 2005-2007: Cisco ICT (A), A2 Maths (D), AS English (D), AS Physics (D)

London Metropolitan University 2007-2009: HND Accounting and Business Management

London Metropolitan University 2009-2011: BA Accounting and Finance 2:2

London School of Business and Finance 2012: ACCA Qualification - F1 to F9 exempt, P1, P2 & P3 (Passed) Option papers (to be completed)

Work Experience

January 2015 to Present Philippine National Bank (Europe) Plc. - Sales Service Associate/MIS

- Processes cash, check and debit card instructions over the counter and apply funds as a remittance. Assists clients in remittance procedures, queries and complaints.
- Prints and reviews electronic credits via Faster Payment, BACs and cash lodgments from correspondent banks and process remittance instructions against credits.
- Ensures all transactions posted to BBS system are properly entered and posted to correct GL accounts. Validates Batch Entry Journal against teller journals, PDQ slips and various A/P suspense accounts.
- Assist in the preparation and submission of accurate and timely reports to PNBE's management and board, Parent banks and Central Bank.
- Assist in the preparation of ICAAP/RCSA for submission to Risk management group
- Assist in the preparation and submission of PNBE's operating and capital expenditure budget and forecast for the year.
- Assist in the accounting unit in the preparation and review of various management and regulatory reports required by the Parent Bank. Bank of England, FCA and UK regulatory bodies.
- Provide cover and assist accounting unit in bank reconciliation of subsidiary ledgers, maintenance of subsidiary financial records, preparing input sheets for daily FX dealings and accounting entries.
- Provide cover and assistance with other operations positions, Adhoc tasks and other tasks required by management.

June 2014 to September 2014

Elite Direct - Sales Executive Leader

This Sales role requires me to absorb and familiarize myself with the products our client wants us to market, and use that knowledge along with sales techniques to pitch the products to customers door to door. Whilst doing this role I have learnt to be more organized, as there is various paper works to keep updated but also how to better manage my time and be self-motivated.

April 2014 to June 2014 (Volunteer) Surrey Camera's - Photographer/Retoucher I would help assist in taking passport or portraits photos, printing and photo editing. The software I used to for I.D's is passport I.D. and Adobe Photoshop and Lightroom for editing. This role has helped utilize and improve my photography and editing skills. I learnt how to interact with customers and how to fulfill their requests.

August 2013 to June 2014 Counter

Orridge Ltd. -

I was a counter where I would scan and count inventory as part of a small team, during a company's annual stock take. I learnt how to work as part of a team and work in a fast and efficient manner.

December 2010 to July 2014 (Part-time)

Genix Imaging Ltd. – Credit Control In this role I would chase debtors via the phone or e-mail and send them monthly statements. I would then update the printed debtors report and record the correspondence on Opera. This role helped my develop my communication skills, maintain client relationships and how to use accounting software Synergist and Opera.

August 2007 to September 2008 (Part-time) Genix Imaging Ltd. – Accounts Assistant During my time in this position I would collect and match invoices to purchase order sheets and enter the invoices onto the Synergist accounting software, then I would allocate the cost on the system to the invoice entered and file completed invoice. The job helped me develop my organizational skills, taught me how to work independently and how to use Synergist software.

Skills

- Good written & verbal communication skills
- Accounting
- Sales
- Interaction skills
- Synergist
- Sage
- Opera
- MS Office
- Interpersonal Skills
- Good at working to deadlines
- Good Organization
- Adobe Photoshop & Lightroom
- BBS & IRSW
- Fluent in Tagalog (native tongue)

Interests & Hobbies

Photography

I have a passion for photography and have been doing it as a hobby for a number of years. During my spare time I build my online portfolio and polish my photography and Adobe Photoshop/Lightroom skills through self-learning. I also assist in Surrey Camera's when I have the opportunity. My goal is to hopefully become a successful free-lance photographer.

Musician

I have learnt how to play various instruments since the age of 8 such as the piano, guitar and drums. On Sundays I play the piano/keyboard for or Praise & Worship band in Streatham and Barking Church of Christ, which I am also currently part of.

Personal Details

Date of Birth: 29 May 1989 Nationality: British Marital Status: Married

Health: Good, Non-smoker

References

Luz Marshall Genix Imaging Accounts Manager Unit 19 Lockwood Industrial Park Mill Mead Road, Tottenham London, N17 9QP

Tel: 020 8885 7320

Marcel Pascua PNBE Deputy Operations Head 238 Vauxhall Bridge Road Victoria, London SW1V 1AU

Mobile: 0788 542 4957